

CONTACT



+359 877 940 083

https://lyubomir-iliev.vercel.app/

ABOUT

Birth date: 01.07.1998

Gender: Male

Citizenship: Bulgaria

I live in: Sofia, Bulgaria

LANGUAGES

NATIVE LANGUAGE: BULGARIAN

English:

Comprehension (Fluent) Speaking (Fluent) Writing (Fluent)

German:

Comprehension (Beginner) Speaking (Beginner) Writing (Beginner)

Spanish:

Comprehension (Beginner) Speaking (Beginner) Writing (Beginner)

LYUBOMIR ILIEV

Junior Front-end Developer



























PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a junior front-end developer with nearly two years of work experience, primarily working with JavaScript, TypeScript, React, and Next.is.

I have hands-on experience with React, Redux, Node.js, Express, and Next.Js. I'm comfortable working with front-end and a little bit of back-end technologies. I have a solid understanding of HTTP Requests, REST APIs, and Git/Git Flow, and I've used Docker for containerizing my projects. I understand the concept of the CI/CD pipeline.

I have base knowledge of the differences between Git Flow and trunk based development. Frequently in my work I use Agile/Scrum environment, using **Jira** for ticket management and **Confluence** for documentation, also I have good understanding of Agile Manifesto.

I've also worked with **Firebase** and **Supabase** for back-end solutions and used tools like **Postman** and **Regbin** for API testing. I have base experience with **OAuth**, and **JWT** for authentication.

One of my biggest learning experiences came from a full-stack project I built using React, JavaScript, SASS, Node, Express, MongoDB, and Docker. It helped me solidify my understanding of the development workflow, debugging, and best practices. I'm comfortable working with Windows and Mac, and my daily tools include VSCode, Chrome DevTools, React Developer Tools, Redux Toolkit, Slack, Discord, and ChatGPT.

I have experience with hosting on platforms like **Firebase** and **Vercel**.

WORK EXPERIENCE

UBBSLA | July 2023 - present

IT COMMUNICATION & DISSEMINATION MANAGER

- Developed React Websites (SPA) with responsive design, ensuring high performance and excellent user experience.
- Implemented authentication using Firebase, state management with **Redux** and **Context API**.
- Integrated external APIs using Axios and Fetch to seamlessly retrieve and display dynamic data, enhancing site functionality
- Designed wireframes and **UI in Figma** before coding, focusing on simple, clean and fast-loading websites.
- Utilized TailwindCSS for efficient styling, and deployed applications on Superhosting to ensure scalability and performance.
- Integration with Google Maps API/Stripe payments and Resend for email notifications.



ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Proficiency in using browser developer tools for debugging code to identify and fix issues.

Willingness to learn new technologies, stay updated with industry trends, and improve skills through self-learning.

Driving License, category: B

LYUBOMIR ILIEV

Junior Front-end Developer

GRAPHIC DESIGN & UI/UX

FREELANCE | (2018-2023)

- Design brand identity for various Bulgarian companies El Shisha, Vapy, Fitty.
- Design logotypes, web pages, banners, flyers, billboards, social media content, menus, woblers and more.

EDUCATION

SOFTUNI | OCTOBER 2023

React.Js Advanced Course

- · Learned Forms, Validations, Routing
- · Learned React Hooks and State Management
- · Learned TailwindCSS, Redux, Firebase, Git
- Passed SOFTUNI React JS 2023 Course with 6.00.

NEW BULGARIAN UNIVERSITY | 2017-2021

Graphic Designer | Level: Professional

Skills accquired:

- Full branding design
- Print design
- · Logo design
- · WEB design
- UI/UX design
- Creativity

NPGPTO "M.V. LOMONOSOV" | 2013-2017

High School | Level: Professional

Skills accquired:

- · Cinema, audio and video technician.
- · Cinematography and photography
- Basic technical education